<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="AdminsAndGroups">
  <title>Admins and Groups</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="adminsAndGroups.xml#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="adminsAndGroups.xml#purpose">Purpose of this Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="adminsAndGroups.xml#adminCreation">Creating an Admin</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="adminsAndGroups.xml#groupCreation">Creating a Group</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="adminsAndGroups.xml#addingUsers">Adding Additional Users to a Group</xref></li>
    </ul>

    <section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on Admins and Groups in the Deployment Inventory Tool.
        Groups in DIT are used to map artifacts (e.g. Documents, Pods, Projects and Deployments) stored in the tool to the respective owners and restricts view/edit functionality to only these owners.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose of this Feature</title>
      <lines>
        For CRUD operations in the DIT UI or through the DIT API, users will need to be associated with one or many groups.

        There are three role types available in DIT:
      </lines>
        <ol>
            <li><b>user</b> : Default role in DIT. Only CRUD operations allowed on artifacts associated with their group.</li>
            <li><b>admin</b> : In addition to 'user' privileges, admins can add/remove users associated with their groups.</li>
            <li><b>superAdmin</b> : This role type has no restrictions.</li>
        </ol>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="adminCreation">Creating an Admin</title>
        <ol>
            <li>When logged in as a superAdmin, the user should click on the username in the top right corner of the tool.</li>
            <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Admins'.</li>
            <li>In the 'Admins' page, click 'Create new admin'.</li>
            <li>Enter the username of the person the user wishes to make an admin in DIT.</li>
            <li>Click 'Save'. This user is now an admin.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
        NOTE: Only users who have logged into DIT at least once can be made admins.
        </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="groupCreation">Creating a Group</title>
        <ol>
            <li>When logged in as a superAdmin, the user should click on the username in the top right corner of the tool.</li>
            <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Groups'.</li>
            <li>In the 'Groups' page, click 'Create new group'.</li>
            <li>The user should enter the name of the group they wish to create in DIT.</li>
            <li>From the 'Group Admin' dropdown, select the user to assign as the admin of this group.</li>
            <li>On the left side of the page, add whichever DIT artifacts (e.g. Document, Pods, Projects, Deployments) that need to be associated with this group.</li>
            <li>On the right side of the page, add the users which will be associated with this group.</li>
            <li>Click 'Save'. This group will be active in DIT.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
        NOTE: Only users who have logged into DIT at least once can be added to a group.
        </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="addingUsers">Adding Additional Users to a Group</title>
        <ol>
            <li>When logged in as an admin, the user should click on the username in the top right corner of the tool.</li>
            <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Groups'.</li>
            <li>In the 'Groups' page, click the edit button beside the group where users are to be added.</li>
            <li>On the right side of the group edit page, add/remove users as required.</li>
            <li>Click 'Save'. This group will now be updated in DIT.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
        NOTE: Only group admins and superAdmins can edit a group's users.
        NOTE: Only users who have logged into DIT at least once can be added to a group.
        </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>

