<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="ProjectFreeAddressFeature">
  <title>Project Free Address API Feature</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="apiProjectFreeAddress.xml#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="apiProjectFreeAddress.xml#purpose">Purpose Of This Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="apiProjectFreeAddress.xml#freeAddress">Free Address API</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="apiProjectFreeAddress.xml#howTo">How To Use</xref></li>
    </ul>
    <section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page describes the purpose of the Project Free Address API feature in the Deployment Inventory Tool and how it works at a high level.
      </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose Of This Feature</title>
      <lines>
        This API was created to help with managing IP addresses for ECFE Deployments.
        Used to find free IP addresses in a network's subnet in a Pod, so it that can be used by a Deployment.
        This will search through each Project that is using the same Pod network, to find the next free IP address available in that network's subnet.
        <b>NOTE:</b> A free IP is defined as any IP that does not resolve to a wildcard URL.
      </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="freeAddress">Free Address API</title>
      <lines>
      This will create a Project or update a Project and returns it's data in JSON, the free IP addresses that was found in the given Pod network's subnet.
      Instead of a normal IP range, it will be an individual IP address in each IP range. Setting that IP address as the start and end IP.
      If creating a Project, it will fill the rest of the Project details with dummy data, as only part is needed is the network - IP ranges section.
      <b>NOTE:</b> Status Code information can be found in API Help Documentation for this API.
      </lines>
      <lines>
        <b>POST API:</b> /api/projects/free_address
        <b>The API parameters:</b>
      </lines>
      <simpletable>
        <sthead>
          <stentry>
            Parameter Name
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Value
          </stentry>
        </sthead>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            pod_name
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Required: The name of the Pod where the network's subnet data is stored.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            network_name
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Required: The name of the Pod's network that has the subnets - required IPv4 and optional IPv6.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            name
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Required: The name of the Project where the assigned IP addresses are stored for Deployment.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            ip_type
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Required: The IP Type - ipv4 or ipv6.
            <b>NOTE:</b> If first time creating a Project, the first request must be IP type ipv4 as the Project requires at least one IPv4 IP Range (IP address).
            Then you can request for free IPv6 addresses.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            number_of_addresses
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Optional: The number of addresses required to be assigned, by default one IP address will be assigned when not provided.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            excluded_addresses
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Optional: List of IP addresses separated by a comma. If ip_type is 'ipv4' enter IPv4 addresses only. If ip_type is 'ipv6' enter IPv6 addresses only.
          </stentry>
        </strow>
      </simpletable>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="howTo">How to Use</title>
      <lines>
        See API Documentation under Projects: /projects/free_address

        The API response is a normal Project API JSON return for the POST/PUT API. Project API information can found in DIT API Help Documentation.
        When deleting address you can use PUT API for a Project, just remove the IP range that contains the IP address.
        The UI can be also used in removing the IP Range that contains the IP address, allowing it be free so can be used by another Deployment.
      </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
