<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="OvercommitFeature">
  <title>Overcommit Feature</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="OvercommitFeature.xml#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="OvercommitFeature.xml#purpose">Purpose</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="OvercommitFeature.xml#overcommit">Overcommit Key Values</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="OvercommitFeature.xml#running">When It Runs</xref></li>
    </ul>
    <section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page describes the ENM SED Overcommit feature in the Deployment Inventory Tool.
        It describes the purpose of the feature and how it works at a high level.
      </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose</title>
      <lines>
        There is an implementation in the SED document to allow for categories of flavor with a mapping to the application to cater for overcommit host aggregates.
      </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="overcommit">Overcommit Key Values</title>
      <lines>
        By checking the "Overcommit Flavors" checkbox, the Deployment Inventory Tool SED document create/edit page will allow the user to switch between overcommit on/off for VM flavor keys.

        If a ECN Managed Config with flavor mapping keys is attached to a SED document, the user will not see the flavor fields and will not need to enter any values.

        For any SED document without an attached Managed Config, the user will be required to enter the overcommit and/or non-overcommit custom flavor values once, before the SED can be saved.

        <b>Note:</b> <i>In order to enable the Overcommit feature, a Managed Config with VM flavor values must first be attached to the SED document. This allows the mappings and substitution of custom flavour names to take place.</i>

        <b>Warning:</b> The deletion or renaming of schema definitions in the ENM SED schema detailed below will result undesired behaviour and or failure of the Overcommit feature.
        Any changes to the ENM SED schema definitions detailed below will required a subsequent update to functionality of DIT to ensure the Overcommit feature continues to perform as expected.
      </lines>
      <simpletable>
        <sthead>
          <stentry>
            Schema Definition Name
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            Inactive Default Value
          </stentry>
        </sthead>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            /definitions/over_commit
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            not_set
          </stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>
            /definitions/not_over_commit
          </stentry>
          <stentry>
            not_set
          </stentry>
        </strow>
      </simpletable>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="running">When It Runs</title>
      <lines>
        The VM flavor keys within the SED will be populated with overcommit/non-overcommit values from either being manually entered or obtained from the ECN managed config.
      </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
