<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="documents">
  <title>Documents</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A document is generated from an associated schema. They are generally used as inputs into deployments such as the SED, the netsim information etc.<br/>
        The following documents make use of the auto population feature to populate all of the keys that it obtains from the associated schema:
        <ul>
          <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/enmSedAutoPopulation.xml">vENM SED</xref></li>
          <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/cenmSedAutoPopulation.xml">cENM SED</xref></li>
          <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/vnfLcmSedAutoPopulation.xml">VNF LCM SED</xref></li>
        </ul>
        <b>NOTE:</b> You can download the Document's content to JSON or YAML from the Document view page, on the top right hand side. See following for more details <xref type="concept" href="../features/parameterDefaults.xml">here</xref>.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Create a new document for the Deployment Inventory Tool</p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#openDocument">Open the Document View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#createDocument">Create New Document</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#enterDetails">Enter the Document Details</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#saveDocument">Save Document</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="documents.xml#schemaVersionUpdate">Schema Version Update</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To create a new document the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Associated Schema already created in the tool</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="openDocument">
        <cmd>Open the Document View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the document view from the nav bar at the top</p>
          <p>Select one of the following document type from the dropdown:
            <ul>
              <li>vENM SEDs</li>
              <li>cENM SEDs</li>
              <li>VNF LCM SEDs</li>
              <li>Managed Configs</li>
              <li>Other</li>
            </ul>
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="createDocument">
        <cmd>Create New Document</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Create new</b> button</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="enterDetails">
        <cmd>Enter the Document Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Enter the details as shown below.</p>
          <p><b>NOTE:</b> Restrictions on the fields are as follows: </p>
          <ul>
            <li><b>Name</b> must be between 5 and 80 characters</li>
            <li><b>Show Snapshots</b> option may be turned on if you want snapshot versions of schemas to be visible in the next step</li>
            <li><b>Schema</b> must be an existing schema</li>
            <li>Based on schema chosen you will need to fill out the document as needed.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Auto Populate</b> option for SEDs may be turned on and off. When fields are autopopulated they are removed from the UI,<br/>
              more info can be found here:
              <ul>
                 <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/enmSedAutoPopulation.xml">vENM SED</xref></li>
                 <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/cenmSedAutoPopulation.xml">cENM SED</xref></li>
                 <li><xref type="concept" href="../features/vnfLcmSedAutoPopulation.xml">VNF LCM SED</xref></li>
              </ul>
            </li>
            <li>If you have an existing document you wish to paste in the <b>Paste Mode</b> can be toggled.</li>
            <li><b><xref type="concept" href="../artifacts/managedConfigs.xml">Managed Configs</xref></b> can be attached using the + symbol.<br/>
             <b>NOTE:</b> Select a category from one of the following choices: size, site or other, in the 'Category' drop-down.<br/>
             This will filter the Managed Configs list by the category selected, for the 'Managed Config' drop-down.<br/>
             This feature is only available for vENM SED Documents.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="saveDocument">
        <cmd>Save Document</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Save</b> button and you will be redirected back to the previous page</p>
          <p><b>NOTE:</b> Document will not save if any fields are invalid (RED in UI)</p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>A New Document is created in the Deployment Inventory Tool.</p>
    </result>
    <section>
      <title id="schemaVersionUpdate">Schema Version Update</title>
      <lines>
        This section will describe what happens when a Document's Schema version changed or updated, either through the UI or via the REST API.

        When editing a Document and changing the Document's Schema version, the newly rendered Document form will change/update based on the content defined in the selected Document's Schema version.
        For vENM SED Documents, this will also update the version of any Managed Configs that is attached to the Document as they are directly associated with the Schema version.
        For more information on <xref type="concept" href="../artifacts/managedConfigs.xml">Managed Configs</xref>.
        If no Managed Configs are attached, then the User will be required to manually enter the required data for any blank key-value pair fields/inputs in order to save the updated Document.
        In the case of non vENM SED Documents, if the selected Schema version introduces new key-value pairs in its content that does not have a pre-defined default value within
        the Schema content will require manual data entry from the User editing the Document.

        When using REST API to update, the User will need to perform the following steps:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Get the Schema ID of new Schema version using the <xref href="/apidocs/#/Schemas/get_schemas" scope="external">Schemas GET REST API</xref>, to get value for "_id" from the returned JSON response body.<br/>
          <b>Example:</b> /api/schemas?q=name=schemaName%26version=schemaVersion&amp;fields=_id
        </li>
        <li>
          Get the Document JSON using the <xref href="/apidocs/#/Documents/get_documents" scope="external">Documents GET REST API</xref>, the Document "_id" value is required for the PUT REST API.<br/>
          <b>Example:</b> /api/documents?q=name=documentName
        </li>
        <li>
          Update the Document JSON, with the new Schema version ID by replacing the "schema_id" value and any other updates required for the Document to use this Schema version.<br/>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Attached vENM Managed Configs will automatically update to the same Schema version as the associated vENM SED Document when it is updated.
        </li>
        <li>
          Add the new updated Document JSON to DIT using the <xref href="/apidocs/#/Deployments/put_deployments__deploymentId_" scope="external">Documents PUT REST API</xref>.
        </li>
      </ol>
      <lines>
        See DIT Help: <xref href="/apidocs" scope="external"><b>API Documentation</b></xref> for more information on how use DIT REST APIs.

        <b>NOTE:</b> The information described in the sections above will depend on whether the Document's <b>Auto Populated</b> feature is enabled, to ensure this process is as automatic as possible.
        It may require other manual action/input to complete, such as adding more IP addresses.

        <b>Upgrade/Rollback</b>
        Content will change based on the Document's Schema version, either by adding/removing key-value pair fields/inputs.
        In some circumstances, vENM SED Document may require new Managed Config(s) to be attached or indeed to be removed based on the desired Deployment configuration state.
        This result in the alterations the contents of the Document, such as additions or loss of data compared to previous version used.

        For any reason, a User needs to recover data from the previous Document Schema combination,
        e.g a Rollback of the Document's Schema version and there was loss of data when the Document was Upgraded/updated to a newer Schema version,
        it can be possible by using the <b>Restore</b> feature found in the Document Logs.

        The Documents Logs can be accessed through the Document View Page by clicking <b>View Log</b> button on the top right corner, where the User can review all the changes made to that Document.
        The User can find a change/state they want to restore, then by clicking <b>Restore</b> button it will restore the Document to the selected change/state.
      </lines>
    </section>
  </taskbody>
</task>
